<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Sam Robbins</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Sam Robbins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 12:14:34 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samrobbins.uk/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Proposal for the GNOME Community Engagement Challenge</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/my-proposal-for-the-gnome-community-engagement-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/my-proposal-for-the-gnome-community-engagement-challenge/</guid><description>This document is submitted in addition to my proposal to provide further detail
This project will aim to train people from zero experience in programming or open source to making contributions to FOSS projects.
Stages This project will consist of a range of stages for the user to go through, I will explain them in more detail
Learning Languages This project will assume zero knowledge, making it accessible for all users.</description></item><item><title>A report on Non-Local Means Denoising</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/image_processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/image_processing/</guid><description>A description of the non-local means denoising algorithm 1 Non local means denoising uses samples from all around the image, instead of conventional denoising which will just look at the area around the given pixel to increase the accuracy of the colour. The reason it does this is due to the fact that patterns and shapes will be repeated in images, meaning that there will likely be an area somewhere else in the image that looks very similar to the patch around the pixel looking to be corrected.</description></item><item><title>To what extent could Quantum Computers Improve On Classical Computers?</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/epq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/writing/epq/</guid><description>Note that this was written during large development in Quantum Computers, and when I was in high school. Both of these to say this won&amp;rsquo;t be perfectly accurate
Introduction Quantum computing is a key concept in computing, as it is a method which allows for far faster computing, beyond the current limits of classical computing. My question is: to what extent could quantum computers improve on classical computers. I chose this topic because of its relevance to the future of computing and the impact it can have on the world.</description></item></channel></rss>