<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hackathon on Sam Robbins</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/categories/hackathon/</link><description>Recent content in hackathon on Sam Robbins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samrobbins.uk/categories/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CV Generator</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/cv-generator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/cv-generator/</guid><description>For this project, I started with the template from magic labs, this allowed me to make sure that my connection to the database and authentication was set up correctly.
Next, I converted the CSS over to use Tailwind CSS, this allowed me to better understand the layout of the application and make changes to designs faster and without unexpected consequences.
The original database structure had two collections, users, and tasks, however, for this project, all the information was related to one user.</description></item><item><title>Easy DMARC</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/easy-dmarc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/easy-dmarc/</guid><description>About This application sets up DMARC on your Vercel domains, and in the process also sets up SPF. In combination, these secure your domain by protecting you from fraud as it is much more difficult for people to send emails pretending to be your domain.
The impact of this for domain owners is that people won&amp;rsquo;t regard emails from them as spam if criminals are sending fraudulent emails pretending to be them.</description></item><item><title>Same Home Different Hacks</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/same-home-different-hacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/same-home-different-hacks/</guid><description>In this project we made an Android app to keep track of electronic components.
Installation The code can be found here https://github.com/samrobbins85/locatemytech, it can be downloaded with
git clone https://github.com/samrobbins85/locatemytech.git We haven&amp;rsquo;t built the packages for this, so you will have to build it yourself using Flutter, instructions can be found here https://flutter.dev/docs/get-started/install.
Pages Homepage When you open the app, you are greeted with the following page
This allows you to see all the components you have.</description></item><item><title>Oxford Digithon</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/oxford-digithon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/oxford-digithon/</guid><description>For this project we created a web browser extension designed to make you less productive. It did this by making productive websites difficult to use and directing you away from them. You can see our demonstration video here:
This was created using the WebExtensions API so should be compatible with browsers other than Mozilla Firefox, but all our testing was done on that.
Installation To install, first download the project from the GitHub linked at the top of the page</description></item><item><title>Durhack 2019</title><link>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/durhack-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:19:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samrobbins.uk/portfolio/durhack-2019/</guid><description>Our project was to build a tool to help people with dementia remember things, this is implemented in various ways, as described below.
Capital One For this, we used the Capital One API to model new transactions coming in and checking if repeat payments are being made. This is done by checking the location and cost of the payment against the previous payments. The reason why this would be useful is that for people with dementia they may forget that they have already bought things, and so buy it again, wasting money.</description></item></channel></rss>